Daniel Stranéus Front-end developer

danielstraneus@gmail.com

+46 704 55 0708

about

Hi, I'm Daniel, a dedicated and enthusiastic 34-year-old front-end developer student from Gothenburg, eager to take my first steps in the tech industry. I'm a father of a young daughter and a slightly larger dog, and as a person, I'm social, curious, creative, and easygoing.

During my years, I've gained lots of experience working as a freelance consultant and in project form. I have been running my own company since 2013, recording and producing music for various independent projects and doing contract assignments for clients. I have also worked with DJ bookings at two venues in Gothenburg in recent years. As a former touring DJ and musician, I've become very comfortable with spoken and written English due to regular contact with various booking agencies and record labels. I am accurate and decent with numbers, as I did bookkeeping at my own company for many years and managed budgets and invoices as a DJ booker. I am hardworking, a great team worker, and always keen to learn and develop new skills.

And now, I am looking for an opportunity to start my new career as a front-end developer. I'd love to bring my dog to your office, but if that's not an option, I am flexible and sure we can work something out. I hope to hear from you soon.

## work experience

Web developer internship @ Lundgren + Lindqvist.

February 2023 - May 2023, Gothenburg, Sweden.

Front-end development. Mostly native JavaCcript + HTML & CSS/Sass, but also some React.js and WordPress. Clients: Röda Sten, Berkley Nordic, Olsson Lyckefors, Slottsholmen.

Web developer internship @ Lundgren + Lindqvist.

August 2022 - October 2022, Gothenburg, Sweden.

Roughly the same as above. Clients: Västtrafik, Norma advokater, Silent socks, Slottsholmen, Bmb agency, Bywind.

Dj & artist bookings @ Zamenhof.

March 2018 - August 2021, Gothenburg, Sweden.

Weekly DJ and artist bookings, as well as more significant events. Playlist curating, managing budgets and invoices.

Dj & artist bookings @ Barabicu.

October 2017 - October 2022, Gothenburg, Sweden.

The same as above + updating content weekly on their website (WordPress).

Music production @ Nudie Jeans Co.

October 2019 - January 2022, Gothenburg, Sweden.

All things music @ Self-employed/Private business.

2013 - present, Gothenburg, Sweden.

Music production for own account as well as consulting assignments for clients. Dj- and live performances in bars, clubs, and festivals in Sweden and Europe. Curating music playlists for clients and bookkeeping.

skills

HTML, CSS/Sass, JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Node.js, Git, Vue.js, Vite, Figma, Bootstrap, A-Frame, WordPress, Express.js, Firebase/Firestore, PHP, color theory & composition, user-focused design & basic design principles, grid-based web layouts, agile working methods, do's & don't's of typography, UX principles.

education

IT-Högskolan. 2021 - 2023. Gothenburg, Sweden.

Front-end development. Courses in Html & css, javascript, frameworks (vue3 & react), agile working methods, Introduction to UX & UI design, fullstack development, CMS, two internship periods and thesis.

University of Gothenburg. 2012 - 2014. Gothenburg, Sweden. Separate courses in Theoretical philosophy, theory of science and sociology.

achievements

Nominated for Swedish Grammy in the music category electro/dance. (2019)

Nominated and awarded the Manifest Prize in the category dance music, a yearly gala Manifestgalan holds. (2019)

Nominated and awarded Göteborgspriset in music, a yearly award from the entertainment magazine Nöjesguiden. (2013)

web https://danielstraneus.github.io/homegithub https://github.com/danielstraneus/email danielstraneus@gmail.com

linkedin daniel-stranéus phone +46 704 55 07 08